The Dead Don't Hurt is a western, drama film directed by Viggo Mortensen.
In the 1860s, fiercely independent French-Canadian Vivienne Le Coudy embarks on a journey with Danish
immigrant Holger Olsen, attempting to forge a life together in the dusty town of Elk Flats, Nevada.
When Holger decides to go fight for the Union in the burgeoning Civil War, Vivienne must
fend for herself, which isn't easy in a town controlled by a corrupt mayor.
Vivienne Le Coudy, played by Vicky Krieps.
Holger Olsen, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Weston Jeffries, played by Solly McLeod.
Alfred Jeffries, played by Garret Dillahunt.
Rudolph Schiller, played by Danny Huston.
Alan Kendall, played by W. Earl Brown.
The Dead Don't Hurt
(French: Jusqu’au bout du monde,
Spanish: Hasta el fin del mundo,
Danish: Til Verdens Ende)
is a 2023 Western film written, directed, and produced by
Viggo Mortensen, and starring Mortensen, Vicky Krieps, Solly McLeod, Garret Dillahunt, Colin Morgan, Ray McKinnon, Luke Reilly, Atlas Green, and Danny Huston.
Mortensen also composed the score to the film.
It is a co-production among Canada, Denmark and Mexico.
The Dead Don't Hurt premiered at the Toronto
International Film Festival on September 8, 2023.
It had a theatrical release in North America on May 31, 2024,
and was released in Denmark on June 13, 2024.
The film received generally favourable reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of immigration, leaving one's family,
sexual violence, american civil war, 1860s.
The tone is emotional.